# Nithin Kashyap Subramanya

Apt. 33, Croi Oige, Athlone | (353) 0872057065 | <a href="https://nithinkashyap.netlify.app">https://nithinkashyap.netlify.app</a> nithinnsk94@gmail.com | <a href="https://github.com/Nithinkashyap">www.linkedin.com/in/nithinkashyap</a> | <a href="https://github.com/Nithinkashyap">https://github.com/Nithinkashyap</a>

## **Objective**

Frontend Developer with 4+ Years of experience in Responsive Web and Application Development. Completed MSc in Data Analytics and seeking new opportunities in Application Security. I have a well-rounded skill set in making secure app development and flair to learn new technologies to enhance web security.

Seeking a software engineering position that makes a positive impact on the environment by building tools and providing services.

### **Education**

MASTER'S IN DATA ANALYTICS | 2021-2022 TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY OF SHANNON, ATHLONE| IRELAND GRADES: 1:1 HONORS

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (INSTRUMENTATION TECHNOLOGY) | 2012-2016 MALNAD COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, HASSAN | KARNATAKA: GRADES: 8.06 / 10

## **Experience**

Front End Developer | Mersus Technologies | Athlone, Ireland May 2022 - Present

- worked on Angular JS, Angular 2+, HTML, Typescript, JSON, NodeJS, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Angular Materials.
- Collated various MVPs and phased them into timed deliverables for monthly sprints
- Worked in remote team and attended daily stand up and generated weekly Gantt chart to track progress.
- Reduced load time of internal legacy website & client websites aby mean of 20%.
- Creation of the Hybrid Web application (PWA) for the Training Management of the employee which works in both Mobile and Desktop.
- Responsible for APK build and testing of the application.

#### Associate consultant | Capgemini Technologies | India

September 2018 – July 2021

- Worked on several internal projects of Alstom as full stack developer.
- Technologies worked on Angular 2+, Angular Js, HTML, JavaScript, Typescript, JSON, NodeJS, CSS.
- Tools used: VS Code, Git, JIRA.
- Developed customized progress tracking reports and dashboard to track KPIs.
- Released with the project team to the modernized stack ready and accomplished POC in 3 months
- Design and developed responsive web application using Angular, JavaScript, Typescript.
- Designed and delivered Hybrid Mobile web applications that work on both Android and IOS devices using the Angular, HTML5, JavaScript and other web development technologies.
- Followed the scrum process with the coordination of the team in Agile Methodology.
- Sphere headed some of the projects for such as Alstom, Moog, and Rolls Royce in creation of the Full stack web application for internal employee management.

#### Software Analyst | I4Global Solutions Pvt Ltd | India

September 2017 - July 2018

- Technologies worked on HTML, Python Flask, Python Django, MongoDB, SQL, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS).
- Creation of a web application from scratch involving security features at front end.
- Creation of a web application for IoT based AR application.
- Development of the Responsive web application using Angular, HTML5, Bootstrap and other web application.
- Mainly used the Python Django and Flask for the development of the backend side of the web application to fetch the data.

## **Skills & Abilities**

- Language: Typescript, JavaScript, Python, C++
- Frameworks: Angular
- Web: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Angular Material.
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB
- Version Controlling: Plastic SCM, GitHub, SourceTree
- Tools & Platform: Eclipse, VScode, Visual Studio.
- Agile: Jira, Kira Align, Confluence

## **Awards & Acknowledgements**

- Awarded Star performer of the year for creation of the Alstom.
- Rising Star award for the creation of the web application for Mercedes

## Reference

Available on Request